eubusiness.com 2019-07-22

# Privacy Statement — EUbusiness.com | EU news, business and politics

**Privacy policy updated May 2018**

## Introduction

EUbusiness Limited respects and is committed to protecting your privacy. We aim to maintain high standards in our use and storage of your personal data, and strive to comply with the [EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://www.eubusiness.com/topics/internet/gdpr-regulation), the UK's Data Protection Act 1998 and other relevant legislation.

To reflect changes in privacy laws, this updated Privacy Statement aims to clearly inform you of how we use your personal data, how we ensure it is kept secure and your choices about its use. We hope this can help you to make informed decisions when using our websites or other services we provide.

In this Statement, references to "we", "us" and "our" refer to EUbusiness Limited. Personal data, as defined by the GDPR, means any information which relates to a living individual who can be identified, either directly or indirectly, from this information - for example your name, email address, postal address, telephone number and other personal details.

From time to time we will update this Privacy Statement, so feel free to refer back to this page regularly. If significant changes are made we will try to notify you.

## Using links to external sites

When you use an external web link on our site, to go from our website to another website, be aware that our Privacy Statement no longer applies. Your browsing and interaction on any other website or your dealings with any other third party service provider, is subject to that website's or third party service provider's own rules and notices/policies. We do not monitor, control, or endorse the information collection or privacy practices of any third parties. This Statement applies solely to Information collected by us through our website or services.

## About us

## Our contact details

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement you can contact us in the following ways:

**Write to us:** Data Protection Officer, EUbusiness Limited, 117 High Street, Chesham, Buckinghamshire, HP5 1DE, United Kingdom  
**Call us:** +44 (0)20 7193 7242 (and ask for the Data Protection Officer)

EUbusiness Limited's registered office is 117 High Street, Chesham, Buckinghamshire, HP5 1DE  
Registered in England and Wales under the company number: 3803196.  
VAT registration number is GB769986828.  
ICO registration number is: Z5381425.

## Collection of your personal data

## Personal data you provide directly to us

We collect personal data from you when you register to the EUbusiness website or enquire about or request a service directly from us. For example you will provide personal data to us when you;

  * register on our website
  * sign up for a digital service
  * request a newsletter

The information we routinely collect will include your contact details (e.g. name, email address, phone number and postal address)

## The lawful bases we rely on

Under the GDPR there are six lawful bases under which organisations can collect, use and store personal data. We rely for our business activities on the Consent and Legitimate Interests legal bases.

Consent - in all circumstances we rely on your specific consent, whereby you actively agree and "opt-in". We will always make it clear how you can withdraw you consent at any time. We specifically rely allow you to

  * register to our database in order to receive the EUbusiness Week email newsletter

Legitimate Interests - for some of our activities we rely on our legitimate business interests to collect and use your personal data. In such cases, we have balanced our interests with yours and do not believe these activities will have a negative impact on your privacy rights and freedoms. We specifically rely on Legitimate Interests to:

  * register your details on our database in order to market your company or organisation's details to the EUbusiness audience.
  * personalise the marketing content we provide you.

## How we use your personal data

## Fulfilment of a service

We will use your personal data for the purposes of fulfilling a service you have requested, which includes:

  * Responding to your enquiries about our services
  * Fulfilling your requests and delivery of a service. For example when you:
  * register to access online content
  * register to access site functionality
  * Administering your account
  * Delivering customer services

## Personalise website content

We sometimes provide tailored recommendations and advertisements to customise the content that you see on our website. To do this, we use cookies and similar technologies provided by our website technology to help us understand how you interact with our websites (e.g. the content you viewed on a previous visit or aggregated website performance analytics). 

## How to stop receiving communications

We won't send you communications if you do not want to receive them. You can stop receiving these messages from us at any time.

**Emails** : There is an unsubscribe link on any email you receive from us.

If you wish to contact us directly about marketing communications you are receiving, please use one of the contact details below:  
 **Write to us:** Data Protection Officer, EUbusiness Limited, 117 High Street, Chesham, Buckinghamshire, HP5 1DE, United Kingdom  
**Call us:** +44 (0)20 7193 7242

## Sharing your personal data

## Legal Disclosure

We may need to disclose your personal data to comply with any legal obligation. These requests will be verified before we consider to share your details.

## Changes to our company

In the event we go through a business transition such as a merger or acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your personal data may be among the assets transferred.

## Social Media, message boards and chat

## Using message boards and chat

Any information which you choose to voluntarily post to our interactive forum, is by nature made publicly available to other users who have access to that portion of our website. We encourage you not to share your personal data and we are not responsible for any information you choose to provide or communicate in such forums. Any disclosures you make are at your own risk.

## Your rights

Under data protection law you have a number of rights. These are aimed at giving you control about how your personal data is used by us.

If you are unhappy with the manner in which we have collected and are using your personal data please do not hesitate to contact us.

If you are concerned with the manner in which we have handled your personal data, you have the right to complain to a supervisory authority. In the UK this is the [Information Commissioner's Office](https://ico.org.uk/).

## Access your personal data

You can request a copy of the personal data we may hold relating to you, and the purposes for which we are using it. This is known as a Subject Access Request. In responding to such a request we may ask for proof of your identity, to ensure we do not inadvertently send your personal data to another person. We will endeavour to respond to any such requests as soon as possible, but at least within one calendar month. Please use our contact details.

## Amend your personal data

If you discover or believe the personal data we hold for you is out of date or incorrect please let us know and we will rectify this as soon as possible.

## Delete your personal data

If you wish for your personal data to be deleted we will do so immediately. We will respond to you as soon as possible, at least within one calendar month of receiving your request.

## Keeping your data secure

## Where we store your personal data

Ensuring your personal data is kept and transferred securely is of the highest importance to us.

We hold your personal data on our secure systems, based in the UK and in the European Union. Where we employ service providers, we have appropriate agreements in place to ensure your personal data is protected.

## How we keep your personal data secure

We are committed to protecting the security of the personal data we hold. We deploy appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure your personal data is kept securely and to prevent any unauthorised access. We have robust procedures and features in place to prevent such unauthorised access.

## How long do we keep your personal data

We hold personal data for a variety of different purposes and the length of time we keep your information for will vary depending on the services we are providing to you. We will only keep your personal data for a reasonable period of time and we base this on the purpose for which we are using it.

There will be circumstances in which we keep a strictly minimal amount of information about you, for example to ensure we can honour an objection to receiving direct marketing. We will also, in specific circumstances, be required to retain personal data for a longer period of time for contractual or legal reasons.

## Reporting security vulnerabilities

We are committed to the privacy, safety and security of our customers. If you discover a potential security vulnerability, we would ask you to please report it just to us in a responsible manner. Please email us at [service@eubusiness.com](mailto:service@eubusiness.com) and we will respond to you as soon as possible. This provides us with an opportunity to work with you and quickly address and resolve any issue. Publicly disclosing a potential vulnerability could put the wider community at risk, and therefore we encourage you to come to us first. We'll keep you informed as we move forward with our investigations.

## Cookie Notice

The aim of our Cookie Notice is to provide you with a summary of the tracking technologies we use and how you can control what is set and when. We keep our Cookie Notice under regular review to best reflect the technology we use on our sites.

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to make this website as useful as possible. Cookies are small text files we put in your browser to track usage of our site, but they don't tell us who you are. 

Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. We use cookies so that we can personalise your experience of the website. If you set up your browser to reject the cookie, you will still be able to use the Website. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). Please note we have no access to or control over these cookies.

Most big websites or internet service providers use cookies, for example to help the site remember your settings such as language, font size and other preferences for how you want to view the site on your computer. The benefit is that you don't have to keep re-entering these details every time you come back to us.

A cookie is a small text file written to your hard drive that contains information about you. Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. We use cookies so that we can personalise your experience of the Website. If you set up your browser to reject the cookie, you may still use the Website.

**Can I reject cookies?**  
If you are worried about cookies, and you want to restrict or block the cookies which are set by the EUbusiness.com website, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how.

However, please be aware that restricting cookies will have an impact on the functionality of the website and the quality of your user experience.

If you want to learn more about cookies, or how to control or delete them, you may also visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) You may also wish to review the guidance provided by the the Information Commissioner's Office [ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/)

**Advertising**  
EUbusiness runs advertising for a wide variety of organisations. We use third-party ad servers to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (NOT including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this website in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Third-party ad servers include Google. These ad servers may attempt to set cookies (see above) on your computer. All these sites stress that information gathered through these cookies is used purely for the purpose of ad delivery, recording and segmentation. They do not use information gathered through their cookies for their own use, and they do not collect any personally identifiable information.

**Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that EUbusiness is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of these third party sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Newswires**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newswires, we ask for contact information such as name and email address.

## Our technology partners

We work directly with a number of technology partners to maintain and enhance our websites. We will update the following table when cookies are added or removed.

**Google DoubleClick**  
We use Google DoubleClick for the delivery and measurement of advertising campaigns.

**Google AdWords**

We use Google AdWords to promote our products and services through Google's advertising opportunities.

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to provide insight into how visitors find and use our web pages so that we can evaluate and develop them.

**Security**  
This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, as will be the case for most of the time that a user is browsing the web.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [service@eubusiness.com](mailto:service@eubusiness.com)

**Correcting/Updating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your postcode), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done by sending an email to [service@eubusiness.com](mailto:service@eubusiness.com)

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
